# HAZEM ABO-DONIA

## SOFTWARE ENGINEERING STUDENT

Brooklyn, New York (+1) 929-327-6812 | habodoni@stevens.edu

#### Education

# **Stevens Institute of Technology**

Hoboken, New Jersey

**B.E. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING** 

September 2022 - Current

- 3.73 GPA
- Stevens Institute of Technology Grant Recipient
- Edwin A. Stevens Scholarship Recipient

## **Brooklyn Technical High School**

Brooklyn, New York

June 2022

- 4.0 GPA (98.09% Cumulative)
- AP Scholar Award
- Sean Cummings Memorial Award Brooklyn Technical High School Football

# Summary

I am currently a freshman at Stevens Institute of Technology. I have experience with both Python and Java, including their implementations in data visualization. I am AutoCAD Certified, ACI (American Concrete Institute) Certified, and CST (Certified Surveying Technician) Certified. Throughout high school I was a part of the Varsity Football Team as well as the Varsity Track and Field team. I am interested in gaining experience in the field of software engineering and development in the New York Metropolitan Area.

#### **Employment**

#### **University Settlement Society of New York**

Brooklyn, New York

**Group Leader** 

July 2022 - August 2022

• Provided children with the opportunity to sharpen their reading, writing, and mathematics skills over the summer through personalized and enriching lesson plans and activities.

#### **Experience**

# **University of Pennsylvania**

**Student Programmer** 

June 2021 - August 2021

- Decreased risk in a stock portfolio through coding a program which clusters various stocks based off market reactions and price movement.
- Utilizes K-Means Clustering (KMC) algorithm, Principal Component Analysis (PCA), and Normalization.

#### **ACE GNY Mentorship Program**

Mechanical Engineering Team

October 2020 – June 2021

- Maximized energy efficiency and reduced installation costs of HVAC systems in a commercial building design.
- In charge of HVAC system and installation process selection.

#### **Steme LLC**

**Student Tutor in Mathematics** 

June 2020 – May 2022

• Provided volunteer tutoring to middle school and high school students in geometry, algebra, and pre-calculus.

## Programs, and Skills

Python, React, C++, Java, TypeScript, JavaScript, Git, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft Excel/Google Sheets, Microsoft Word/Google Docs, Microsoft PowerPoint/Google Slides, Autodesk Inventor, Autodesk AutoCAD, Team Management, Project Scheduling, Problem Solving Ability, Communication, Project Estimation

#### Certifications

American Concrete Institute (ACI) Certified Concrete Tester (June 2022), Certified Surveying Technician (CST) Certified Surveyor Level 1 (June 2022), Autodesk AutoCAD Certified (January 2022)

#### Languages

English (Native), Arabic (Advanced), French (Intermediate)

HAZEM ABO-DONIA · RESUME